<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aum Mhapankar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aum Mhapankar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/myresume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/myresume/</guid>
      <description>AUM MHAPANKAR aummhapankar@gmail.com
EDUCATION The University of Texas at Austin Bachelor of Sciences and Arts, Biology, BSA Honors
Health Science Scholars Honors Program
Business Healthcare Certificate
Health Professions Certificate (Fall 2016 – Spring 2020)
 EXPERIENCE MD Anderson – Clinical Research Finance Intern; Houston, TX (Summer 2019)
 Worked with the Clinical Research Finance team to help ensure that clinical research at MD Anderson was funded accurately and allocated institutional funds to specific departmental research projects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>About me I am glad to present a little bit about myself. My hometown is Grapevine, TX and I am 21 years old. I have a younger sister and cousins in California, India, and Australia.
For more information about my education, interests, experience, accomplishments, and skills, feel free to check out my resume:
 Resume  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I&#39;ve been working on</title>
      <link>/blog/things-i-ve-been-working-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/things-i-ve-been-working-on/</guid>
      <description>RStudio Here are links to projects I have worked on that involved using RStudio to combine datasets, run biostatistical tests, and generate plots to model data and determine trends between variables.
http://127.0.0.1:7240/Project1/
http://127.0.0.1:5046/projects/
Python Some of the Python material I have worked recently on has involved basic statistical analysis of datasets such as faithful in which our input code was:
import pandas as pd faithful=pd.read_csv(&amp;ldquo;https://vincentarelbundock.github.io/Rdatasets/csv/datasets/faithful.csv&amp;quot;)
type(faithful) faithful.head()
print(&amp;ldquo;Max eruptions: &amp;ldquo;) max(faithful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have been working on during my Computational Biology Course:
  Project 1 (Data Wrangling and Exploratory Analysis)
  Project 2 (Modeling, Inference, Prediction)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Data Wrangling and Data Exploration I chose the datasets, Suicide and GBSG2, as they gave the suicide rates and Breast Cancer data in Germany, respectively. The variables included in the Suicide dataset include sex, age, and methods for committing suicide. The Breast Cancer dataset includes tumor size, age, survival time, and more variables. I combined them by age to see the effect of age on these various variables. I am not entirely sure whether there will be associations with age groups that have greater cancer rates and higher rates of suicide, but this association is certainly highly possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(dplyr) library(vcd) data(&amp;quot;Suicide&amp;quot;) library(TH.data) data(&amp;quot;GBSG2&amp;quot;) germany_age &amp;lt;- Suicide %&amp;gt;% inner_join(GBSG2, by=&amp;quot;age&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% na.omit() germany_age$Freq&amp;lt;-NULL germany_age$age.group&amp;lt;-NULL germany_age$method2&amp;lt;-NULL ?Suicide ?GBSG2 I chose to use the germany_age dataset, a joint dataset of the Suicide and GBSG2 datasets from the vcd package. The germany_age dataset is composed of 13 variables and 2394 observations, and it has data on suicide rates in Germany based on age, sex, and method of suicide. It also contains data from a breast cancer study in Germany, and the data are combined to be compared by age.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>